<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>For the King, and both Houses of Parliament, sitting at Westminster, and for every member thereof to read</title>
         </titleStmt>
         <editionStmt>
            <edition>
               <date>1661</date>
            </edition>
         </editionStmt>
         <extent>Approx. 47 KB of XML-encoded text transcribed from 13 1-bit group-IV TIFF page images.</extent>
         <publicationStmt>
            <publisher>Text Creation Partnership,</publisher>
            <pubPlace>Ann Arbor, MI ; Oxford (UK) :</pubPlace>
            <date when="2014-11">2014-11 (EEBO-TCP Phase 2).</date>
            <idno type="DLPS">A40187</idno>
            <idno type="STC">Wing F1821</idno>
            <idno type="STC">ESTC R181334</idno>
            <idno type="EEBO-CITATION">18778436</idno>
            <idno type="OCLC">ocm 18778436</idno>
            <idno type="VID">108348</idno>
            <availability>
               <p>To the extent possible under law, the Text Creation Partnership has waived all copyright and related or neighboring rights to this keyboarded and encoded edition of the work described above, according to the terms of the CC0 1.0 Public Domain Dedication (http://creativecommons.org/publicdomain/zero/1.0/). This waiver does not extend to any page images or other supplementary files associated with this work, which may be protected by copyright or other license restrictions. Please go to https://www.textcreationpartnership.org/ for more information about the project.</p>
            </availability>
         </publicationStmt>
         <seriesStmt>
            <title>Early English books online text creation partnership.</title>
         </seriesStmt>
         <notesStmt>
            <note>(EEBO-TCP ; phase 2, no. A40187)</note>
            <note>Transcribed from: (Early English Books Online ; image set 108348)</note>
            <note>Images scanned from microfilm: (Early English books, 1641-1700 ; 1653:14)</note>
         </notesStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <biblFull>
               <titleStmt>
                  <title>For the King, and both Houses of Parliament, sitting at Westminster, and for every member thereof to read</title>
                  <author>Fox, George, 1624-1691.</author>
               </titleStmt>
               <extent>[2], 22 p.   </extent>
               <publicationStmt>
                  <publisher>Printed for Robert Wilson ...,</publisher>
                  <pubPlace>London :</pubPlace>
                  <date>[1661]</date>
               </publicationStmt>
               <notesStmt>
                  <note>Dated and signed (p. 13): "... this 13th day of the 3d month, 1661. G. Fox, J. Stubbs, F. Howgil, H. Fell, R. Hubberthorn, R. Scostrop."</note>
                  <note>Date of publication suggested by Wing.</note>
                  <note>Reproduction of original in the Huntington Library.</note>
               </notesStmt>
            </biblFull>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      <encodingDesc>
         <projectDesc>
            <p>Created by converting TCP files to TEI P5 using tcp2tei.xsl,
      TEI @ Oxford.
      </p>
         </projectDesc>
         <editorialDecl>
            <p>EEBO-TCP is a partnership between the Universities of Michigan and Oxford and the publisher ProQuest to create accurately transcribed and encoded texts based on the image sets published by ProQuest via their Early English Books Online (EEBO) database (http://eebo.chadwyck.com). The general aim of EEBO-TCP is to encode one copy (usually the first edition) of every monographic English-language title published between 1473 and 1700 available in EEBO.</p>
            <p>EEBO-TCP aimed to produce large quantities of textual data within the usual project restraints of time and funding, and therefore chose to create diplomatic transcriptions (as opposed to critical editions) with light-touch, mainly structural encoding based on the Text Encoding Initiative (http://www.tei-c.org).</p>
            <p>The EEBO-TCP project was divided into two phases. The 25,368 texts created during Phase 1 of the project (2000-2009), initially available only to institutions that contributed to their creation, were released into the public domain on 1 January 2015. The approximately 40,000 texts produced during Phase 2 (2009- ), of which 34,963 had been released as of 2020, originally similarly restricted, were similarly freed from all restrictions on 1 August 2020. As of that date anyone is free to take and use these texts for any purpose (modify them, annotate them, distribute them, etc.). But we do respectfully request that due credit and attribution be given to their original source.</p>
            <p>Users should be aware of the process of creating the TCP texts, and therefore of any assumptions that can be made about the data.</p>
            <p>Text selection was based on the New Cambridge Bibliography of English Literature (NCBEL). If an author (or for an anonymous work, the title) appears in NCBEL, then their works are eligible for inclusion. Selection was intended to range over a wide variety of subject areas, to reflect the true nature of the print record of the period. In general, first editions of a works in English were prioritized, although there are a number of works in other languages, notably Latin and Welsh, included and sometimes a second or later edition of a work was chosen if there was a compelling reason to do so.</p>
            <p>Image sets were sent to external keying companies for transcription and basic encoding. Quality assurance was then carried out by editorial teams in Oxford and Michigan. 5% (or 5 pages, whichever is the greater) of each text was proofread for accuracy and those which did not meet QA standards were returned to the keyers to be redone. After proofreading, the encoding was enhanced and/or corrected and characters marked as illegible were corrected where possible up to a limit of 100 instances per text. Any remaining illegibles were encoded as &lt;gap&gt;s. Understanding these processes should make clear that, while the overall quality of TCP data is very good, some errors will remain and some readable characters will be marked as illegible. Users should bear in mind that in all likelihood such instances will never have been looked at by a TCP editor.</p>
            <p>The texts were encoded and linked to page images in accordance with level 4 of the TEI in Libraries guidelines.</p>
            <p>Copies of the texts have been issued variously as SGML (TCP schema; ASCII text with mnemonic sdata character entities); displayable XML (TCP schema; characters represented either as UTF-8 Unicode or text strings within braces); or lossless XML (TEI P5, characters represented either as UTF-8 Unicode or TEI g elements).</p>
            <p>Keying and markup guidelines are available at the <ref target="http://www.textcreationpartnership.org/docs/.">Text Creation Partnership web site</ref>.</p>
         </editorialDecl>
         <listPrefixDef>
            <prefixDef ident="tcp"
                       matchPattern="([0-9\-]+):([0-9IVX]+)"
                       replacementPattern="http://eebo.chadwyck.com/downloadtiff?vid=$1&amp;page=$2"/>
            <prefixDef ident="char"
                       matchPattern="(.+)"
                       replacementPattern="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/textcreationpartnership/Texts/master/tcpchars.xml#$1"/>
         </listPrefixDef>
      </encodingDesc>
      <profileDesc>
         <langUsage>
            <language ident="eng">eng</language>
         </langUsage>
         <textClass>
            <keywords scheme="http://authorities.loc.gov/">
               <term>Society of Friends --  Apologetic works.</term>
            </keywords>
         </textClass>
      </profileDesc>
      <revisionDesc>
         <change>
            <date>2013-11</date>
            <label>TCP</label>Assigned for keying and markup</change>
         <change>
            <date>2013-11</date>
            <label>SPi Global</label>Keyed and coded from ProQuest page images</change>
         <change>
            <date>2014-02</date>
            <label>Ali Jakobson</label>Sampled and proofread</change>
         <change>
            <date>2014-02</date>
            <label>Ali Jakobson</label>Text and markup reviewed and edited</change>
         <change>
            <date>2014-03</date>
            <label>pfs</label>Batch review (QC) and XML conversion</change>
      </revisionDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text xml:lang="eng">
      <front>
         <div type="title_page">
            <pb facs="tcp:108348:1" rendition="simple:additions"/>
            <p>FOR THE KING, AND BOTH HOUSES OF Parliament, Sitting At WESTMINSTER, And for every MEMBER thereof to READ.</p>
            <p>
               <hi>LONDON,</hi> Printed for <hi>Robert Wilſon</hi> in <hi>Martins Le-Grand,</hi> near <hi>Alderſgate.</hi>
            </p>
         </div>
      </front>
      <body>
         <div type="text">
            <pb facs="tcp:108348:2"/>
            <pb n="1" facs="tcp:108348:2"/>
            <p>FRiends! O Friends, in the power of God dwell, that laſt<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>eth for Ever, which doth Remain and Abide; And minde the Higher Power, which God hath Ordained, which <gap reason="illegible" resp="#KEYERS" extent="1 word">
                  <desc>〈◊〉</desc>
               </gap> over all Tranſgreſſors, Sinners, and Evil-doers; which Law, and Higher Power, was not made for the Righteous, but Sinners and Tranſgreſſors, to be a Terror to them, and for the puniſhment of them, and for the Praiſe of them that Do well. Now them that Do Well, the Righteous, this Law and Higher Power was not made for, and doth not take hold upon them; to which Higher Power ever Soul muſt be ſubject: the Higher Power, I ſay, that is Higher than all Tranſgreſſors, Evil-Doers, and the Divel, who went out of the Truth, that led into Sin and Tranſ<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>greſſion: Therefore to Sin and Evil people are not to yeild them<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſelves; but their Souls unto the Higher Power, as I ſaid be<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>fore, that goes over Sin and the Devil, the Author of it, to this Power muſt the Soul be ſubject. Therefore you Rulers and Magiſtrates are to put a difference between the Precious and the Vile, the Righteous and the Wicked, ſuch as the Law was made for, Sinners and Tranſgreſſors (for which cauſe it was ad<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ded) and the Righteous which it was not made for; for this Higher Power that goes over all Sinners and Tranſgreſſors, was not made for the Righteous, which the Immortal Soul muſt be ſubject to; this Immortal Higher Power, that Higher Power an<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſwereth, and is one with the Spirit and Witneſs of God, that witneſſeth for him, againſt Sin and Tranſgreſſion, of the Law and Power of God in every One.</p>
            <p>Secondly, Keep all in the Fear of God, departing from Sin and Evil, that ye may receive Gods Wiſdom from Above, that is Pure and Gentle, and eaſie to be Intreated, and is full of Mercy and Goodneſs, which is not Earthly, Senſual, nor Divelliſh; but keeps from Hard-heartedneſs; and that with that Wiſdom you may be Ruled, and Order, and Govern with, and by all things under your Hands to Gods Glory, by which Wiſdom all things were Made and Created, that to the Lord you may be a Bleſſing, and a Sweet ſavour in your Generation, and in the Hearts of all People, anſwering the Witneſs of God in them all, that you may be Eys to the Blind, Legs to the Lame, taking away every Weight,
<pb n="2" facs="tcp:108348:3"/>and Heavy burthen, and breaking the Jaws of the Wicked, that would Rend and Tear the Innocent to pieces, that in that you may be a Mouth to the Dumb, and a Strength to them who can<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>not Help themſelves; in that you will get the Honor of God, and bow the Hearts of the people.</p>
            <p>Again, Let Wickedneſs and Violence be ſtopt, Swearing, Oaths, Drunkenneſs and Prophaneſs, of which much abounds in the Land, that Truth and Righteouſneſs may be ſet Up and Eſtabli<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſhed, and run down the ſtreets; for that is it which eſtabliſheth the Kingdom; for the Higher Power is that goes over all, the Divel, and all the powers of Darkneſs, and over Sinners and Tranſgreſ<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſors, which anſwereth that which all men do Tranſgreſſe.</p>
            <p>And let no one be Perſecuted and Impriſoned for Worſhip<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ping of God in Spirit &amp; Truth, which the Divel is out of; ſeeing Chriſt and the Apoſtles did not give any Command or Example that they ſhould be Impriſoned, Perſecuted and Baniſhed, though there hath been much Perſecution about the Church-Miniſtry and Worſhip, and Ceremonies, ſince the dayes of the Apoſtles, and Chriſt in the Fleſh; though, as I ſaid before, from them they have had no Example, nor Command from the Apoſtles and the Church in the primitive times to do ſo; ſuch as will Grieve the Spirit, Quench the Spirit, Deſpiſe the Propheſie, were forbidden by the Apoſtles.</p>
            <p>And let there be no Perſecution nor Impriſonment of them that be in differences in their Opinions in Religion, which all Profeſſing the Name of Chriſt, whoſe Command is, to all them who Follow Him, and Own Him, that they ſhould love Enemies: Let this command be Obeyed and Minded, and not Troden un<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>der Foot; for that is it which overcomes Enemies.</p>
            <p>And again, Do to all men as you would have them do unto you, for this is the Law and the Prophets: And if this had been minded in the whole Chriſtendom; that is to ſay, the Law and the Prophets, and Practiced and Obeyed, and not troden under foot the Life of it, by them who have Profeſſed the Words, there would have been better Order in the whole Chriſtendom and Creation; for this we ſay, and know, <hi>He that is born of the Fleſh, will Perſecute him that is born of the Spirit.</hi> Let not this Birth be found amongſt them that profeſs themſelves Chriſtians and Pro<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>feſs Chriſt Jeſus, and own the Church in the primitive time,
<pb n="3" facs="tcp:108348:3"/>which was among the Apoſtles: Now the fruit of the birth born of the fleſh, is <hi>Perſecution,</hi> &amp;c. the fruit of the birth, born of the Spirit, is <hi>Love, Peace, Gentleneſs, Righteouſneſs, Goodneſs,</hi> and <hi>Temperance,</hi> &amp;c.</p>
            <p>Let there be no compelling about Worſhip, about Dayes, Meats, and Religion, nor forcing of a Maintenance for a Mini<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſtry; for ſo doing there is no example among the Apoſtles, nor command neither from Chriſt nor them; but on the contrary all things muſt be done in Love and Bounty as amongſt the Apoſtles, and in the Church in the Primitive times, <hi>For freely they had re<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ceived, and freely they were to give:</hi> This was the command of Chriſt Jeſus, who is the ſame to day, yeſterday, and for ever. <hi>Chriſt Jeſus,</hi> who is the <hi>Head</hi> of the Church, and <hi>Chiefe Biſhop,</hi> who did not give forth any Law or Command, or Example to his Embaſſadours, Apoſtles, and Friends, for them to force, or com<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>pel any about worſhip, or Religion, or Maintenance, or about Dayes, or Meats, or Drinks; from the cheif <hi>Shepherd,</hi> the great <hi>Biſhop,</hi> there was no Command nor Example for ſo doing, nor from his Diſciples, nor Apoſtles, nor the Church in the Primi<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tive Times; but they brought people off the Figures, Tipes, and Shadows, and from their affections on things below, to Chriſt <hi>Jeſus</hi> the ſubſtance; and moreover ſaid, That the body which is the Church, was to edifie it ſelf in love, of which Church Chriſt Je<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſus is the <hi>Head,</hi> who is the <hi>Biſhop, Prophet, Prieſt,</hi> and <hi>King,</hi> to Rule, to Teach, and to Offer; and Chriſt Jeſus is the End of the firſt Covenant, the firſt Prieſt-hood, which had the Tithes, and the Offerings: For there was the Tithe which was the Heave-Offering, which Chriſt ended, and the Prieſthood, and the Law, and the Commandement that gave them, <hi>Heb.</hi> 7.</p>
            <p>So the Church of Chriſt ſtands in the end of the Law, firſt Co<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>venant, and Prieſthood, as is ſaid, Chriſt is the end of the Law for Righteouſneſs Sake, to them that believe; and his Church is made up of Believers, which paſſeth from Death to Life. So all the Miniſters, and Teachers in the whole Chriſtendome that will not preach without a Bag, and without a Magiſtrates Staff to Puniſh, and a Bag to relieve them, and will fill their Bag of ſuch they do no work for, and of ſuch you have experience, and do, and may know, that they are not like unto the Diſciples, which Chriſt ſent forth without Bag or Staff, and ſuch as was a<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>mongſt
<pb n="4" facs="tcp:108348:4"/>the Apoſtle<gap reason="illegible" resp="#KEYERS" extent="1 letter">
                  <desc>•</desc>
               </gap>, whom they ſaid muſt not be Strikers, nor Perſecutous, nor Covetous, nor greedy of filthy lucre, and they muſt be proved, before they muſt Teach. So <gap reason="illegible" resp="#KEYERS" extent="1 span">
                  <desc>〈…〉</desc>
               </gap> Scriptures of Chriſt and the Apoſtles, and there you may ſee the Life, Do<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ctrine and Commands, by which you may meaſure the Miniſters and Teachers of Chriſtendome; and though in the Law among the Jewes, by the Law they were to put to death the Blaſphe<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>mers, falſe Prophets, and the like; which Law Chriſt ended, and came to ſave mens Lives, and to deſtroy the Devill and his works, for this purpoſe was he made manifeſt; for the Devill was the Authour of Blaſphemy, and falſe Prophets, whom Chriſt de<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſtroyes; Blaſphemy, and falſe Prophets are the Divers works; yet Chriſt ſaved mens Lives, and rebuked the Zeall of his Diſ<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ciples, that would have mens lives deſtroyed; And the Apoſtles, which were the Miniſters, and Teachers, and Embaſſadours of the Lord Jeſus Chriſt, their Weapons were Spiritual, and not Carnall, and they did not wreſtle with Fleſh and Blood, but with ſpirituall wickedneſs, and the powers of darkneſs; ſo the men being ſpirituall, and their weapons ſpirituall, wreſtling not with fleſh &amp; blood, their hands were kept clean, &amp; fiſts not wicked, who could pray to God, liſting up Holy Hands: theſe were no com<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>plainers about Church-Maintenance, Worſhip, and Religion; neither were they Strikers: but all in the whole Chriſtendom, ſince the Apoſtles days &amp; the Church in the Primitive Times, that have killed, perſecuted, forced, impriſoned about Church-wor<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſhip, and Religion, Maintenance, and have wreſtled with fleſh and blood, and diſtroyed creatures, which have been the Work-man<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſhip of God, inſtead of wreſtling with the powers of darkneſs, and ſpirituall wickedneſſes; theſe have not been ſpirituall men, neither have they had ſpirituall weapons; neither have their hands, nor fiſts been holy and clean; and ſo they have not been agreeable, nor according to the Apoſtles, nor Chriſt Jeſus, and his Church in the Primitive Times; but contrary to his Mind, Doctrine, and Commands, and his Church, of whom he is Head.</p>
            <p>The Law that was among the Jews, commanded them to wor<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſhip at <hi>Jeruſalem,</hi> and come up to the Temple, or at the Moun<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tain of <hi>Samaria;</hi> but Chriſt Jeſus, who ends that Law which brought people up to worſhip; then he ſaith, <hi>That the Hour is
<pb n="5" facs="tcp:108348:4"/>come, and then was that they that worſhip the Father, muſt worſhip him in the Spirit and in the Truth;</hi> For ſuch were they the Father ſeeks to worſhip him. Now every one that worſhips the Father in Spi<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>rit and Truth, muſt come to the Spirit their own particulars, that mortifies ſin and evill, and into the Truth in their own in<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ward parts, and this <gap reason="illegible" resp="#MURP" extent="1 letter">
                  <desc>•</desc>
               </gap>i<gap reason="illegible" resp="#MURP" extent="2 letters">
                  <desc>••</desc>
               </gap>el<gap reason="illegible" resp="#MURP" extent="1 letter">
                  <desc>•</desc>
               </gap> them from the Will-Worſhippers, and from the worſhip of the Divell, that is out of Truth, where all the compelling worſhip is.</p>
            <p>And concerning our Meetings, Chriſt and his Diſciples they met in Houſes, yea, the Wiſe Men Miniſtred to Chriſt, and his Mother in the Stable; and Chriſt and his Diſciples met in the Wilderneſſes, and in the Mountains, and he bids them go into the High-Wayes, and the Hedges, and <gap reason="illegible" resp="#KEYERS" extent="1 span">
                  <desc>〈…〉</desc>
               </gap> the Houſe tops, and to the Markets; and the Apoſtle in the midſt of <hi>Mars-</hi> Hill, and ſometimes in the Temple, and in the Synagogues, and amongſt the Heathens, to bring them off Tipes; Figures and Shadows, and their own inventions, to Chriſt the Subſtance: Therefore now, that Chriſtians ſhould hinder <gap reason="illegible" resp="#KEYERS" extent="1 span">
                  <desc>〈…〉</desc>
               </gap> that profeſs and own the Name of Chriſt, for Meeting together and Edifying and <gap reason="illegible" resp="#MURP" extent="4 letters">
                  <desc>••••</desc>
               </gap>ding upon another, (though they all profeſs the Name of Chriſt) this is to quench the Spirit, and limit the Holy One, and is againſt the edifying of the body itſelf in Love, and the building up one another in the Holy Faith, in Love<g ref="char:punc">▪</g> who are not to forſake the Aſſembling together, nor the Edifying of one another, by how much <gap reason="illegible" resp="#MURP" extent="1 span">
                  <desc>〈…〉</desc>
               </gap> day doth appeal: Now they that be againſt this, be not in the day, <gap reason="illegible" resp="#KEYERS" extent="1 word">
                  <desc>〈◊〉</desc>
               </gap> in the night, and are contra<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ry to the Apoſtles Doctrine, and the Practice of the Church in the Primitive Times: Theyrefore though there be Diverſities of Gifts, and divers Opperations, and ſeveral Gifts, and ſeveral O<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>pinions, and Judgements, who with ſpiritual weapons with ſpiri<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tual men, are theſe to be ordered, and <gap reason="illegible" resp="#KEYERS" extent="1 word">
                  <desc>〈◊〉</desc>
               </gap> with Carnal, with Clubs, and Seaves, and Priſons; for theſe Weapons are of the <hi>Heathens, Jews; Judaſes,</hi> and of <hi>Cain,</hi> who was the firſt that killed and per<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>fecuted about Religion and Worſhip upon the earth, whom God ſaid, was <hi>A Vagabond;</hi> and the Apoſtle <hi>Paul</hi> ſaid, <hi>Woe be to them that go in his way,</hi> who ſaid his Weapons <hi>were ſpirituall,</hi> and ſo not like <hi>Cains,</hi> who ſlew his Brother contenning his Faith and Doctrine: Therefore conſider, who are of Faith, and have the Faith, they have the Shield, the ſpirituall Weapons; and who
<pb n="6" facs="tcp:108348:5"/>have the Word of God, they have the Sword of the Spirit, and the Hammer, and the Fire, that which is to cut down, and Hammer down, and bar up that which is contrary to the word, which makes ſeparation from God; and theſe are the ſpiritual Weaponed men.</p>
            <p>And Chriſt Jeſus ſaid, who hath all power in Heaven and Earth given to him, who is the end of the Prophets, Law, Firſt Cove<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>nant, and Firſt-Prieſthood: <hi>It hath been ſaid of them of the Old time, Thou ſhalt not Forſwear thy ſelf, but ſhalt perform thy Oath to the Lord: But I ſay unto you, Swear not at all, by Heaven nor Earth, nor any other Oath; but in all your Communication, let your Yea, be Yea, and your Nay, Nay; for whatſoever is more commeth of Evil.</hi> And likewiſe the Apoſtle <hi>James,</hi> who followed Chriſts Com<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>mand, and obeyed Chriſts Doctrine, ſaith, <hi>Above all things, my brethren, Swear not, neither by Heaven, nor by any other Oath.</hi> There<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>fore we and they, that keep out of Evil and Condemnation, can<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>not Swear, but rather Obey the Doctrine of our Saviour Chriſt Je<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſus, and the Apoſtle, who is the Son of God: and if the Angels command us to Swear, we cannot; for the Son of God com<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>mands us the contrary, and to Him the Angels muſt bow. If <hi>Solomon,</hi> who was a King, and <hi>David,</hi> and <hi>Moſes,</hi> or <hi>Abraham,</hi> commands us to Swear, we cannot; for the Son of God com<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>mands the contrary, who was before <hi>Abraham</hi> was, and is a greater than <hi>Solomon,</hi> whom <hi>David</hi> called Lord, even CHRIST JESUS, who is King of Kings, and Lord of Lords: And if the Jewes Laws commands us to Swear, we cannot; for Chriſt Jeſus, who ends the Jewes Law, and the Oath, and redeems to God, com<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>mands us we ſhould not Swear: ſo our Redeemer and Saviour, who is our Life and Truth, our Way, our Rock and Salvation, his commands we cannot Tranſgreſſe: And if they that be Chri<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſtians, and do profeſs the Name of Chriſt, do perſecute us for Obeying of Chriſt Jeſus his Command, and becauſe we will not Tranſgreſſs his Command, and the Apoſtles, we ſay, The will of the Lord be done. And we do ſay, it is not well for Chriſtians to Perſecute, or Impriſon ſuch as Obey the Command of Chriſt, who in their communications uſe <hi>Yea</hi> and <hi>Nay,</hi> according to his Doctrine; and if their <hi>Yea</hi> be not <hi>Yea,</hi> and their <hi>Nay, Nay;</hi> and if we break our <hi>Yea,</hi> and break our <hi>Nay,</hi> then let us ſuffer as much for breaking of That, as others for breaking their <hi>Oath:</hi> This Impriſoning and Fining us, becauſe we cannot Swear, to the
<pb n="7" facs="tcp:108348:5"/>breaking of the Command of Chriſt, hath got up ſince the A<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>poſtles dayes; for which doing ſo, and practice, among the Apo<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſtles and Church in the Primitive Times, there is no Com<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>mand nor Example.</p>
            <p>And we deſire to have, (who pay their Taxes and Aſſeſsments) as much Liberty as <hi>Stage-Players,</hi> and <hi>Mountebanks,</hi> and <hi>Ballad-Singers,</hi> who meet together in hundreds, to the Diſ-honour of God, and likewiſe all other Playes which we do not hear are cal<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>led Tumultuous Meetings, as ours are who meet together to E<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>difie one another in that which is good, to worſhip God; And this is allowed in the Scripture, <hi>They that feared the Lord, ſpake often together,</hi> whom the Lord heard, and theſe were caſt out and hated in the dayes of <hi>Iſaiah;</hi> for they were ſuch as trem<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>bled at Gods Word, but <hi>Sports</hi> and <hi>Playes,</hi> the Scripture does not allow of; but the Lord by his Servants Rebuked ſuch.</p>
            <p>Let no one be put to Death for Cattle, or Mony; but let them <hi>Reſtore;</hi> and if they have not wherewith, let them Labour till they have, in the thing that is good, and ſo that they may have ſpace to Repent; and this is agreeable to the Scrip<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tures.</p>
            <p>Let all Writs and Indictments, Subpaena's, Warrants, have no more put in them, then the things that are truly charged againſt him; and all Laws drawn in a ſhort Volume, that all may know them, that all things may be kept wholeſome and ſweet, that to the Lord God you may be a good Savour; and let all Priſoners that have layen four or five yeares in Goales, Priſons, and Hou<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſes of Correction, be brought out to a Tryal, before their Accu<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſers, and ſee who there is that Accuſes them, and let them not lye to periſh in Goales, and Priſons, that mercy and Tenderneſs, Juſtice and Truth may flow among all people, that to the Lord you may be a good Savour and in your Generations, and a Praiſe to God.</p>
            <p>And again concerning Religion, and ſeverall Opinions, and Judgements in the Worſhip of God; let every <gap reason="illegible" resp="#KEYERS" extent="1 word">
                  <desc>〈◊〉</desc>
               </gap> ſpeak his Judgment, ſpeak his Opinion.</p>
            <p>Let all Magiſtrates keep peace with his Magiſtrates Sword, and keep down the Hand and Fiſt of People, that they ſhall not ſtrike with their Fiſts, Clubs, Swords and Staves; for Envious Perſons, Strikers, and Man-Slayers, the Law is againſt: and let
<pb n="8" facs="tcp:108348:6"/>the Magiſtrates be like <hi>Gameliel;</hi> who ſaid, <hi>If it was of God, it would ſtand; if it was not, it would fall;</hi> who ſaid to others, <hi>They ſhould take heed, leſt they were found fighters againſt God;</hi> ſo let the patience of an Heathen be an Example to Chriſtians, which in<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>deed them that profeſſe the Name of Chriſt, ſhould be beyond <hi>Gamaliels;</hi> ſo whatſoever Opinions, Judgements, that are not of God will fall; but take heed, do not fight againſt it, leſt you be found fighters againſt God; and conſider Chriſts mind, who ſaid, <hi>Let the Tares and the Wheat grow together till the Harveſt:</hi> Therefore you may ſee he ſtopped his Diſciples from pulling up, leſt they ſhould pull up the <hi>Tares</hi> and <hi>Wheat</hi> together, and ſo prevented that danger; therefore mind that Caution: And <hi>Saul,</hi> before he was converted, in his firſt birth was a Perſecutor, run<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ning up and down from the <hi>Chiefe Priests,</hi> with his Packet of Let<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ters, to hale and perſecute from City to City, ſuch as lived in the Life of <hi>Christ Jeſus;</hi> but of this Action he Repented, when he was converted; and the Apoſtle had no ſuch Agents as the Jews Chief Prieſts had, with packets of Letters to perſecute and hale them from City to City; and they that have done ſo ſince the dayes of the Apoſtles, gone up and down with their packets of Letters haling, and perſecuting ſuch as have been in the Life of <hi>Christ Jeſus,</hi> have been like the unconverted <hi>Jews,</hi> and <hi>Priests,</hi> and <hi>Saul;</hi> but not like the Church in the Primitive Times, and converted <hi>Paul.</hi> So here you may ſee the converted, and the un<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>converted; he that is in the birth born of the Spirit, and he that is in the birth born of the Fleſh.</p>
            <p>And concerning of what Sort of People the Lord made uſe of, and ſpake to in the <hi>Old Testament;</hi> and concerning alſo what ſort his Son CHRIST JESUS made uſe of, and ſpoke to in the <hi>New Testament;</hi> in the <hi>Old,</hi> ſuch as were <hi>Herds-men, Plow-men, Keepers</hi> of <hi>Cattel, Gatherers</hi> of <hi>Fruit, Threſhers</hi> of <hi>Corn, Keepers</hi> of <hi>Sheep:</hi> and theſe were hated of the World; as <hi>Abel,</hi> a <hi>Keeper</hi> of <hi>Sheep;</hi> and <hi>Moſes,</hi> a <hi>Keeper</hi> of <hi>Sheep;</hi> and <hi>Jacob,</hi> a <hi>Keeper</hi> of <hi>Sheep;</hi> an<gap reason="illegible" resp="#MURP" extent="1 letter">
                  <desc>•</desc>
               </gap> 
               <gap reason="illegible" resp="#MURP" extent="1 letter">
                  <desc>•</desc>
               </gap>he Prophet <hi>David,</hi> a <hi>Keeper</hi> of <hi>Sheep;</hi> and theſe confounded the World, and ſuch like as theſe ſpeak forth the Scriptures. And Chriſt choſe <hi>Fiſher-men</hi> for <hi>Soul Gatherers; Paul,</hi> a <hi>Tent-Maker,</hi> &amp;c. And theſe had not been at Univerſities, and Schools of Learning to Train them up in; but Chriſt Jeſus was their Teacher, who did not call many of the great Doctors, and
<pb n="9" facs="tcp:108348:6"/>Learned men, who is the ſame to day, yeſterday, and for ever, both God and Chriſt. And if he make uſe of the ſame, and ſuch like now, be not offended; if he fill the earth with his Knowledge, and cover it with the ſame as the water the Sea, let none be Trou<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>bled and Offended: <hi>For all the Children of the Lord ſhall be taught of Him,</hi> and <hi>in Righteouſneſs ſhall they be establiſhed, and great ſhall be their Peace,</hi> according to <hi>Eſaiahs</hi> Propheſie, <hi>Eſay</hi> 54. Which Propheſie many of Us do witneſs: And likewiſe we do witneſs the Promiſe of God, who ſaid, he would make <hi>A New Covenant, not according to the Old;</hi> For he ſaid, <hi>I will put my Law in their Minds, and put them in their Hearts; whereby they ſhall not have need to ſay to one another, Know the Lord; for all ſhall know Him, from the Greatest to the Least; and I will be to them a God, and they ſhall be me to a People, &amp;c.</hi> And this we Witneſſe. And ſo we need not to have Teachers, ſaying, <hi>Know the Lord.</hi> So therefore we need not be compelled to ſuch Teachers, who would keep us alwayes in Teaching, that we might be alwayes paying of them, who keeps us alwayes Learning; under whoſe Teaching we were never able to come to the Knowledge of the Truth; under whoſe Teaching we were kept in Reprobation from Faith, which Chriſt is the Author of now, unto whom we look, and need not ſay to one another, <hi>Know the Lord.</hi> And Chriſt is the <hi>Head</hi> of every Man, who is <hi>Our Head,</hi> who is <hi>Our Leader,</hi> who is <hi>Our Way,</hi> and we need not another. For God now ſpeaks unto us by his Son, who is the Heir of all things; upholding all things by his Word and Power; of whoſe Grace have we received, who is <hi>Our Covenant</hi> with God and <hi>Our Life;</hi> of whoſe Kingdom we are Heirs, that is Everlaſting without End; and in whoſe Domini<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>on is <hi>Our Life,</hi> that is an Everlaſting Dominion, which hath no End; which is over all that has an End. And <hi>Our Croſs</hi> of Chriſt is the <hi>Power of God,</hi> that crucifieth us from the World, and keeps us over and from the power of Ungodlineſs that is therein; and for this <hi>Croſs</hi> ſake are we Perſecuted; in which <hi>Croſs</hi> is <hi>Our Fellowſhip;</hi> and <hi>Our Goſpel</hi> it is the <hi>Power of God,</hi> which is the <hi>Everlasting Goſpel,</hi> which laſts for Ever, in which we are Shod; and <hi>Our Helmet</hi> is <hi>Salvation,</hi> and <hi>Our Fellowſhip</hi> is in the Spirit, which Baptiſeth into <hi>One Body,</hi> which plunges down the <hi>Corruption</hi> that is got up ſince the Tranſgreſſion, which ſeparates from God; in which Spirit is our Fellowſhip, in which
<pb n="10" facs="tcp:108348:7"/>we are made all to Drink; And into this we would have all People to come, that they might have Fellowſhip and Union, and Drink; And the <hi>Head</hi> of <hi>Our Church</hi> is CHRIST JESUS, who hath all Power in Heaven and in Earth given unto him: Chriſt, who is Gods Wiſdom to Govern it, who is the Rock to Uphold it above all Storms and Tempeſts: And our Religion is Pure, from Above, and we cannot Own that which is Below, amongſt whom the Profeſſion lieth in Lips and Mouth, and Tongues at Liberty, and Hearts afar Off from God; Tongues at liberty, and not Bridled: And our Manners lies in the Power of God, and Spirit, and the Light of <hi>Christ Jeſus,</hi> that keeps us from Evil words, that corrupts Good Manners. So where the Good Manners are not, the Tongue is not Bridled.</p>
            <p>And again, let no one be Perſecuted, nor Impriſoned, nor Fined, for not putting off his Hat or Cap, which ſatisfieth the Luſt of the Eye, and the Luſt of the Fleſh, and the Pride of Life, which is of the World, and not of the Father: So we cannot ſeek Honour one of another, as the Phariſees did, to whom Chriſt ſaid, <hi>How can you Believe, who ſeek Honour one of another, and not the Honour which comes from Above onely?</hi> Therefore who Beleeve, and are the Beleevers, and ſeek the Honour which comes from God onely, which is from Above, Such ſeek not the Honour that is Below, as the Phariſees did one of another. So the Beleever is the <hi>Converted,</hi> born of God, and will not Perſecute, for not having that Honour that is Below given to him; neither will he ſeek it, as the Unconverted Phariſees did <hi>John.</hi> 5.</p>
            <p>And again, for we to Honour all men, is to have all men in Eſteem: Therefore we Eſteeming all men, do Love them, and not Hurt them, and ſo are come into the minde of CHRIST JESUS, who commands <hi>TO LOVE ENEMIES,</hi> who is the SAVIOUR of all men, but eſpecially thoſe that believe: And the mind of God is, That all men ſhould come to Repentance, and to the Knowledge of the Truth; but all Chri<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſtendome have profeſſed that Scripture, and ſaid, <hi>Honour all men</hi> &amp;c. Which hath been <hi>Hat, Lip</hi> and <hi>Foot,</hi> but have <hi>Hurt, Murthe<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>red, Killed</hi> One another, their Heads, and Princes; and theſe have been with the Honour below, which God hath, and will lay in the duſt; for to <hi>Honour all Men,</hi> is to have <hi>all Men in Esteem,</hi>
               <pb n="11" facs="tcp:108348:7"/>and to have <hi>all Men in Esteem,</hi> is to <hi>hurt</hi> no <hi>Man:</hi> and if this had been ſo in the whole Chriſtendom practiced, then would never a man in the whole Criſtendome have been hurt by one another; but every man in the whole Chriſtendome would have Loved one another as himſelf; and they that Rule well, ſuch are worthy of <hi>Double Esteem,</hi> more than they that are Ruled, which all are to be had <hi>in Esteem</hi> which are <hi>honoured:</hi> and if this practice had been followed in the whole Chriſtendome, there had been more Love, &amp; Unity, which hath been loſt ſince the Apoſtles dayes, which practice was amongſt them, which the Honour of a Magi<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſtrate lies in the Higher Power, and likewiſe the Honour of all men, which every ſoul muſt be ſubject to the Higher Power; and in that power <hi>they honoured all Men,</hi> and in that power they give them that rule Well <hi>Double Honour,</hi> which before this <hi>Honour</hi> is the <hi>Humility;</hi> ſo he that will have the <hi>Honour,</hi> muſt have the <hi>Hu<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>mility,</hi> for it goes before the Honour, which Higher Power brings him to be humble, in which Higher Power he hath the Ho<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>nour, and this is from above, <hi>higher honour,</hi> in the <hi>higher power</hi> high<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>er, I ſay, and above the divel, and all his works, and workers &amp; his tranſgreſſors, a higher power is higher then them all, is over and above them all, and it is above the Honour which is below, which God will ſtain; and in this power we do Eſteem all men, and give Double Eſteem to them that Rule Well; and ſo Honour them not with that Honour which the World Honours them withall, which is Below; and the ſame that will Honour them with Hat, and with Knee, will Diſhonour them and God both; which they with that Honour in the Power of God, which is from Above, which Honour they Honour withall, will not Diſhonour God nor Man.</p>
            <p>Now you have Tried us, by Long and Cruel Impriſonments, in Dungeons, and Holes, and Vaults, and Cellars, and Stables, and Houſes of Correction, where we have been thruſt upon heaps, and have not had ſo much Liberty in many places as Fellons; Nor have not had ſo much Room in many places, as to lie down one by another. Through which Cruel Suffering and hard Uſage, twenty one have died, and beſides many more are weak; and not ſuffered to have neceſſaries to come in; and many Tradeſ<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>men, and Sea-men, Merchants, and Husbandmen, their Cal<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>lings and Families have been Neglected, and Waſted. So you
<pb n="12" facs="tcp:108348:8"/>have not acted towards us as Chriſtians, nor minded <hi>Solomons</hi> Councel, who ſaith, <hi>A Kingdome is Maintained by Husbandry.</hi>
            </p>
            <p>So theſe twenty one which are dead, their Innocent blood, through cruel Sufferings, we leave to the Lord to require; and can ſay, <hi>The Lord forgive you, and lay nor theſe things to your Charge:</hi> but that ye may do ſo no more, and not bring Innocent blood upon your ſelves and the Land. For the Lord will make Inqui<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſition for blood; <hi>For Precious are the Death of his Saints in his Eies.</hi> Though we are killed all the day long, and are as the Sheep for the Slaughter; and by theſe Long, and Cruel and Hard Sufferings, of above five Thouſand, ſince the Kings Arri<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>val; From whom we did not look for ſuch Meaſure of Suffer<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ings: and three Thouſand of us have Suffered by the Powers before him; which many of them yet lye in Priſon, and have lain this four or five years, in the Names of the Protectors, and Common-Wealths, for Conſcience ſake, and yet by you have not been ſet at Liberty, though they do not lye in your Names, in your Goales.</p>
            <p>And notwithſtanding, all this Trial of us, by which ye have Tried us under cruel Sufferings, and have not found us Guilty of Plots, Inſurrections, Tumults againſt the King, or the Peace of the Nation, or any Mans Perſon or Eſtate, Our Liberty is not Reſtored to us, as to meet together to Worſhip God accor<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ding to the Kings Word and Declaration, which is but a Juſt thing: We not being found to be ſuch (as his Proclamation Limits) who have made ill uſe of his Indulgence, neither have we Forfeited our Liberty: Therefore it is not Equity to Num<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ber us amongſt ſuch who have Forfeited their Liberty. Now therefore, our defire is, That a Proclamation may be ſet forth that we may have our Liberty, ſeeing we have not Forfeited it according to the Kings Word, and that men may not run up<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>on us with Arms, Clubs, and Staves, which are not Chriſtians Weapons, to run upon people who are met together to Worſhip God: which is the Spiritual mens place to medle with Spiritual Things. And it is the Son of Perdition that ſits in the Temple of God, which Exalts himſelf above all that is called God, who muſt be deſtroyed by the Brightneſs of his coming, and by the Breath of his Mouth: And have cryed the Miniſters, we cannot ſerve our bellies of the people, if we have not the Magiſtrates Swords to
<pb n="13" facs="tcp:108348:8"/>compel and forbid people not to meet together to Wor<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſhip God and pray together, and declare his Goodneſs, and confeſs his Name; for with the mouth confeſſion is made to Salvation; You may as well bid us deny GOD our SALVA<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>TION, and not confeſs our ſelves to be Chriſtians, and to live without the fear of God; for they that feared God, met of<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ten together, as in <hi>Malachy,</hi> whom the Lord heard: And is not the Scripture full of theſe ſayings, that the Saints ſhould tell of the Wonders of God, and declare what God had done for their Souls? And what! Chriſtians limit us from this. And muſt we be limited from confeſſing Chriſt before men? Is not Chriſt a<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſhamed of them before his Father, that be aſhamed of him be<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>fore men? And muſt Sons and Daughters be limited from Propheſying, upon whom the Lord hath poured his Spirit? And doth not the Apoſtle ſay, <hi>Quench not the Spirit?</hi> And is not this his Doctrine? And doth not God ſay, <hi>Limit not the Holy One,</hi> and <hi>Deſpiſe not Propheſy?</hi> And doth not the Apoſtle ſay, <hi>God is not Worſhiped by the Handy-works of Men,</hi> by that which mens hands have wrought, &amp; ſet up for Worſhip? That is a large word but God is worſhipped in Spirit and Truth; This is Chriſt, Doctrine: And let none be compelled to the publique Worſhip, nor Fined, nor Impriſoned; for that was never the Practice nor Doctrine of Chriſt, nor the Apoſtles, to compel any againſt their own Conſciences, who were not firſt perſwaded by the Spirit of God.</p>
            <closer>
               <dateline>
                  <hi>This is from the People of God, called</hi> Quakers, <hi>and Subſcribed by <g ref="char:V">Ʋ</g>s,</hi> 
                  <date>
                     <hi>this</hi> 13th <hi>day of the</hi> 3d Month, 1661.</date>
               </dateline>
               <signed>
                  <list>
                     <item>
                        <hi>G. Fox.</hi>
                     </item>
                     <item>
                        <hi>J. Stubbs.</hi>
                     </item>
                     <item>
                        <hi>F. Howgil.</hi>
                     </item>
                     <item>
                        <hi>H. Fell.</hi>
                     </item>
                     <item>
                        <hi>R. Hubberthorn.</hi>
                     </item>
                     <item>
                        <hi>R. Scostrop.</hi>
                     </item>
                  </list>
               </signed>
            </closer>
         </div>
         <div type="postscript">
            <pb n="14" facs="tcp:108348:9"/>
            <head>POST-SCRIPT.</head>
            <p>LEt no one be Perſecuted about Religion, Worſhip, Miniſters-Maintenance; let all be done freely in Bounty and Love, as it was among the true Churches in the Primitive Times; for <hi>Cain</hi> killed his Brother about Worſhip, Religion and Sacri<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>fice, which <hi>Cain</hi> built a City; by that you may ſee he was a Ruler; for which Fact, Killing his Brother, God ſaid, <hi>He was a Fugitive, a Vagabond in the earth, for Murthering and Killing his Brother.</hi>
            </p>
            <p>The Jews by the Law of God, were for to kill Here<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ticks and Falſe Prophets that were ſetters forth of ſtrange Gods; and this they were to do by the Law of God, which Law of God Chriſt ended, who hath all Power in Heaven, and in earth given unto him; who was the chiefe Magiſtrate upon the earth: And the Jews in a pretence of killing the Falſe Prophets, they killed the True Prophets, and ſtoned them to death, before Chriſt the great Prophet came in the Fleſh, and they crucified him, and cauſed many of the Apoſtles to be Perſecuted and Killed, and they thought they did God good ſervice, having Gods Law to kill ſuch that ſet forth ſtrange Gods, or another way: therefore they thought they did God good ſervice in killing the Prophets, killing the Son, killing the Saints; and ſo do all Religions elſe, as do the Antichriſts and Papiſts, that have killed and put to death ſo many hundreds, that were contrary minded, in Religions, which with them was Vagabonded from God, by which the earth
<pb n="15" facs="tcp:108348:9"/>hath been ſtained with the blood of the Innocent, in Killing, Perſecuting, and putting to Death about Reli<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>gion ſince the Apoſtles dayes; <hi>And the Church went into the Wilderneſs,</hi> Rev. 12. <hi>Yea, the very earth hath not yeilded her increaſe, but it hath brought a Curſe upon it;</hi> though they have been Sacrificers and Killers, as <hi>Cain,</hi> which Sacrifice God hath no reſpect to; but to ſuch as are of <hi>Abels</hi> Faith, that do not kill, but have the ſpi<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ritual Weapons: Therefore let there be an Univerſall Liberty about Religion, and let no Chriſtian perſecute a Chriſtian, ſeeing all profeſſe Chriſt in words; but let them be ruled with Spirituall Weapons, and their Reli<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>gion defended with ſpirituall Weaponed Men, elſe they are but like <hi>Cain,</hi> the <hi>Jews, Judas,</hi> and the <hi>Papiſts,</hi> and not like the Apoſtles in the Primitive Times; who ſaid, Their Weapons were not Carnal but ſpiritual.</p>
            <p>And if you ſay, how ſhould we know the true Diſci<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ples of Chriſt Jeſus? here is their Mark, they are ſuch that love one another; hereby they are known to be Diſci<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ples: and if you do ſay, How ſhall we know the true Be<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>leevers in Chriſt Jeſus? theſe are they that are paſſed from Death to Life, and ſuch love both Brethren and Enemies.</p>
            <p>Now though there were Haters, and Perſecutors, de<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>nyers of the Reſurrection, Blaſphemers of God and Chriſt, who had all power in Heaven and in Earth, given unto him, the Chief Ruler upon the earth, which ended the Law, did not Perſecute any, nor cauſe any to be put Death, to be Perſecuted or Baniſhed by the Jews Law, but he ſaid, <hi>Love Enemies:</hi> here they dif<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>fered from the Phariſees, here was their mark of being Children of the moſt high God. And the Apoſtle ſaith,
<pb n="16" facs="tcp:108348:10"/>
               <hi>He that is born of the Fleſh, will perſecute him that is born of the Spirit:</hi> So here is each birth, (and they which are the Children of the Fleſh, theſe are not the Children of God,) the one will perſecute, and the o<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ther is the perſecuted, and the Apoſtle bids <hi>Overcome Evill with Good.</hi>
            </p>
            <p>So all the true Worſhippers that Worſhip God in the Spirit, in the Truth, which the Devill is out of, theſe cannot perſecute any about Religion, Church and Wor<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſhip; but are the ſpirituall Men, and have the ſpiritu<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>all Weapons, and theſe are like unto the Apoſtles in the Primitive Times: Therefore as the Papiſts have perſecuted about their Church, Religion and Sacrifice; for which example they have had none from the Apo<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſtles in the Primitive Times: Let none follow their Examples, but Chriſt, who ſaid, Love Enemies, and wreſtle not with Fleſh and Blood; but Chriſt ſaid to the Diſciples, who would have had Fire come down from Heaven, to conſume them who were contrary minded, he reproved them, and tells them they knew not what Spirit they were of.</p>
            <p>Wherefore they that do deſtroy mens lives about Wor<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſhip, Church and Religion, do not know what Spirit they are of; wherefore how can we truſt our Bodies, Souls and Spirits into the Hands of ſuch as know not what Spirit they are of themſelves?</p>
            <p>Let there be no forced Maintenance to the Miniſters that profeſſe the Goſpel, but let all be done by Free<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>neſs and Bounty, as it was in the Apoſtles days; for the Papiſts that ſet up Tythes, and pretend the Law of God hath been ſince the Apoſtles dayes; which Law of God Chriſt ended, and Tythes both, as in <hi>Heb.</hi> 7.</p>
            <pb n="17" facs="tcp:108348:10"/>
            <p>Let no one be put to Death for Cattel, or Money, or ſuch things as many be; but let them Live to reſtore Four Fold, or be Sold for their Theft, and to work with their Hands in the thing that is Good, according to the Apoſtles Doctrine and Command of God; for the Law of God is Juſt and Equal, and Perfect, going over all Tranſgreſſion, anſwering the Tranſgreſſed Prin<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ciple in all, and to all men to do as they would be done by.</p>
            <p>And many ſay the Lords Prayer, <hi>Forgive us our Treſpaſſes, as we forgive them that Treſpaſs againſt us,</hi> then fall a Perſecuting and Revenging, although with their Lips they ſay theſe words; for if they had for<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>given, there had never been Perſecution in the whole Chriſtendom ſince the Apoſtles dayes.</p>
            <p>Wherefore they that ſay theſe words, <hi>Forgive us our Treſpaſſes, as we forgive them that Treſpaſſe againſt us,</hi> and doe not the things, are the Sayers, and not Doers, like the Phariſees.</p>
            <p>Wherefore conſider, for CHRIST JESUS, the Lord of Life, the King of Glory, Lord of Heaven and Earth, is come to Reign, to reward every one according to their Works, and give every one a Reward for his Doings. Wherefore Fear, and Dread the Lord God of Hoſts, of Heaven and Earth: For now you have time Prize it, ſpend it not as a Tale, or as one that dreameth, paſs it not away; for man muſt periſh, or will periſh, living in the Earth, out of the Life, being in the Separation from God. Wherefore Fear and Tremble before the Living Mighty God of Heaven and Earth, <hi>The Lord of Hoſts is his Name.</hi>
            </p>
            <p>Now whereas there is a great Noiſe of Stopping and
<pb n="18" facs="tcp:108348:11"/>Impriſoning the Leaders, and the Heads of the <hi>Quakers.</hi> Thus Chriſt is their Head, <hi>And the Head of every man</hi> (as in <hi>Corinthians</hi>) and Chriſt in the Female, and he is the Head there, who is their Leader to God, who deſtroyes the Devil, and his Works, and all the Powers of the world cannot limit him. Chriſt, who hath all Power in Heaven and in Earth given unto him, and He in the Male and Female, is King, is Head, is the Leader, is their Commander, is their Wiſdom, Juſtification and Sanctification, is their Redemption, and the Reſur<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>rection, bringing them to God, into a Life that is Ever<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>laſting, without End. So Chriſt is the Prophet, and King, a King to Rule, a Prophet to Teach, an ever<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>laſting Prieſthood, that offers up the Spirituall Sacrifice to God; He is in Man, in the Male, in the Female: So Chriſt is in all except they be Reprobates; and if he be within, he is the Leader to the Father, he is the Teacher, he is the Head, he is the Elder, he is the Firſt, he is the Laſt. So here is no ſuch thing among the <hi>Quakers,</hi> which know their Election before the World began, whoſe Salvation is wrought out with Fear and Trembling, that are Redeemed from all them that have caſt the Fear of God behind them, and live without it, without God in the world, and no Aſſurance of Election, who Hire men to Lead them and Teach them, where there is Exalting, and Heads many over them, whom Chriſt is the Head, to Condem<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>nation that hate the Light: Among them are the ſeveral Maſters like Phariſees; but to the Diſciples he ſaid, <hi>It ſhall not be ſo among you,</hi> who is the Head of his Diſci<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ples, their Teacher and Leader, ſo they have but one Head, if they be Ten Thouſand times Ten Thouſand,
<pb n="19" facs="tcp:108348:11"/>Chriſt is the Head in the Male and Female; and here is no Exerciſing Lordſhip among them over one another, as among the Gentiles; and the Apoſtate Chriſtians are got into the Lordſhip, and are Offended if they will not give them Earthly Honour: And the Lord ſaith, <hi>His Children ſhall be taught of him, and they ſhall be Eſta<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>bliſhed in Righteonſneſs:</hi> And theſe are them which the Teachers and Profeſſors of the world perſecute. And the Lord ſaith, <hi>Every one that hath heard, and learned of the Father, cometh to the Son:</hi> And the Apoſtle ſaith, <hi>They have the Anointing within them to teach them; and they need not man to Teach them, but as the ſame Anointing did Teach them.</hi> And this he Wrote to the Saints concerning them that did ſeduce them: And he told them many Antichriſts and Falſe Prophets were gone out into the World, and thoſe be them that be alwayes Teaching them, that they may be alwayes paying them: but the True Apoſtles brought people to the <hi>Anointing within them;</hi> and told them, <hi>That the Grace of God, which brought Salvation, did Teach them.</hi> And God had put his Law in their Mindes, and writ it in their Hearts, whereby they they need not ſay one to another, Know the Lord, for they all know him, from the leaſt to the greateſt: And the Apoſtle ſaid to the <hi>Hebrews,</hi> how that God had ſpoke to our Fathers by the Prophets at ſundry times; but now hath ſpoke unto us, by, or in his Son, which is the Teacher, whom we witneſs (thouſands) to be our Teacher, and Head, and Leader, <hi>Why perſecutes thou me,</hi> ſaith Chriſt; It is hard for ye to kick againſt that which pricks you in your own Conſciences, ſaith Chriſt, in the Male, in the Female; you caſt into Priſon, you do
<pb n="20" facs="tcp:108348:12"/>not Viſit Chriſt there, you do not Cloath him, you do not Feed him, nor give him Drink: Oh! where will you appear? where will your end be, that do not juſtly? did not Chriſt lay theſe plainly down, ſay<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ing they caſt him in Priſon, and did not Viſit him, nor Relieve him when he was Sick? and yet now you in Chri<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſtendom, do not ſee, and are ſo ignorant of him, where he is made manifeſt in his Members in the Male and Female, who is their Head, and Teacher, and Leader into the Righteouſneſs and Truth, whom you ſhould Love; and you caſt them into Priſon for meeting toge<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ther, having nothing againſt them to inſnare them, and yet you profeſs the Name of Chriſt: now if you did pro<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>feſs the Name of Chriſt in Truth, you would love Ene<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>mies, [if they were your Enemies,] and not perſecute them that are taught of God, and Chriſt is their Head; for God let <hi>Cain</hi> have the liberty of the earth, though he was a Fugitive it it, for murthering his Brother: And God let the Heretick <hi>Nimrod,</hi> that began to build <hi>Ba<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>bel,</hi> have liberty in the earth; and Scoffing <hi>Iſmael</hi> have liberty in the Earth, in the Wilderneſs.</p>
            <p>And becauſe the Jews had the Law of God, who had the Signes, Types, Figures and Shadows, by which they were to kill Blaſphemers, and falſe Prophets, that drew away from God; which Law and outward Carnal Wea<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>pons was a figure of the true Spiritual Weapons, and of the Word of God, Chriſt Jeſus that deſtroyes the Devil, and Blaſphemers, and falſe Prophets, which were gone out from God; and this was done by the Spi<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ritual Weapons; yea by the Sword, that proceeds out of his mouth: therefore the Chriſtians are to love Ene<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>mies.</p>
            <pb n="21" facs="tcp:108348:12"/>
            <p>For they that go about to take away the Heads and Leaders of the QUAKERS, as they think, they go about to take away CHRIST, for he is the Head, not many Heads, but their Head and Leader; for the many Heads is the Beaſt, and is in the World, and is in the Fall from God; for Chriſt is their Head and Leader and Way (in the Male and Female,) and Life, and Truth; who is the way to God the Father; who is the onely King, Omnipotent, Immortal and Everlaſting, Glory be to him for evermore; who hath ſent his Son to be our Teacher, Saviour, Redeemer, and our Way, and Truth, and Life, and our Reſurrection, and our Offering, and great Sacrifice, by which we are Sanctified and Perfected for ever; who is alſo our Prophet, Prieſt and King, and his Command we can<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>not deny, but muſt confeſs him before Men, even Chriſt Jeſus, who hath ſpoken to us in theſe laſt dayes, who ends the Law, and Prieſts, Temples, Tithes, Offerings, Sacrifices, firſt Covenant, and Ceremonies, and Sha<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>dows, and the Carnal Weapons, which do kill about Religion; and the Son of God bids us <hi>Love Enemies:</hi> Gods Son bids us <hi>Love Enemies,</hi> and <hi>Swear not at all.</hi> And this is the Son of God that ſpeaks from Heaven; they that ſpeak from Earth, Kill and Per<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſecute one another, and ſay, <hi>We muſt Swear,</hi> and brings it from the <hi>Jewes</hi> Law, which Chriſt ends, or from the Heathens below. But we muſt confeſs Chriſt before men, For he hath poured out of his Spirit upon all Fleſh, and his Sons and Daughters, and they ſhall and do Propheſie; and the Teſtimony of Jeſus is the Spirit of Propheſie; and this is our Teſtimony of Jeſus, <hi>Even the Spirit of Propheſie;</hi> and God hath
<pb n="22" facs="tcp:108348:13" rendition="simple:additions"/>given to us of his Spirit, by which we know his Things; and the manifeſtation of his Spirit is given to every man to profit withall; and they that <hi>grieve</hi> and <hi>quench the Spirit,</hi> do not profit by the Spirit, but to their Condemnation; and if any one have not the Spirit of Chriſt, he is none of his.</p>
            <trailer>THE END.</trailer>
            <pb facs="tcp:108348:13"/>
         </div>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI>
